We just saw an example experiment where three out of four metrics had
我们刚刚看了一个实验
a statistically significant difference at the alpha = 0.05 level for
四个指标中有三个有统计意义上的差异
each metric individually.
每个指标的 α = 0.05
But when I combined the metrics and tested for significance using
但当我把指标结合起来
the Bonferroni correction, none of the metrics were significant.
用 Bonferroni 方法来测试重要性 没有哪个指标是重要的
So how do I actually make a recommendation here?
那么 我该给个什么建议呢？
The Bonferroni method is likely to be too conservative,
Bonferroni 方法可能太过保守
since I expect the metrics to be correlated,
因为我认为指标是相互联系的
but my rigorous results say that the change isn't significant.
但是严格的结果表明变化不大
The rigorous answer here is to use a more sophisticated method than
严格的结果将使用比 Bonferroni 更复杂的方式
Bonferroni, ideally one that takes into account the fact
它会考虑到实际情况
that the metrics are likely to be correlated.
指标可能是相互联系
There's a list of other possible methods in the instructor's notes.
在讲师注释中有一系列其它可用的方式
There's also another type of strategy here that's different
也有其他类型的方案 有别于选择一个独立的 α
than just choosing an individual alpha, and I'll talk about that in a minute.
稍后我将谈论到
Ideally, I would have decided what method to use when designing
我需要决定好采用什么方法 在设计实验时
the experiment, and taken that into account when sizing.
在决定尺寸时要将其考虑在内
Practically speaking,
实际上
this type of situation may come down to a judgment call.
这种情况可以归结为主观判断
If I have a lot of experience running different experiments with these
如果我有用这些指标做各种实验的经验
metrics, then I would have a good intuition for
我将有敏锐的直觉
whether these results are likely to persist or not.
是否这些结果会保持不变
In this case, I would need to communicate that to the decision
在这个例子中 我需要与决策者进行沟通
makers to make sure they understand the risk.
确保他们了解这个风险
There may also be other factors here such as business strategy.
也可能还有其他因素 例如商业战略
The decision makers may want to launch the change if there are strong,
决策者可能会想推出这个变化
strategical reasons to launch it.
如果有强烈的战略原因要推出它
Or otherwise they may choose to abandon it,
否则他们可能选择放弃它
given the uncertainty of the results.
所以结果是不确定的
Or if it's not urgent, they may want to run another set of experiments
或者不急的话
that are more adequately powered.
他们可能想要进行另一组更有效力的实验
So what's the other strategy that I mentioned a minute ago?
那么 我刚刚提到过的另一个战略是什么呢？
Well, the methods we've used up to now try to control the probability that
我们使用的方式 想要控制
any metric shows a false positive.
任何一个指标出现假正例的可能性
I've been calling this probability the overall alpha.
我们把概率称为总的 α
But it's more commonly called the family wise error rate, or FWER.
更常用的叫法是一组聪明的误差率或 FWER
Another approach is to loosen that and say you're okay with some false
放松的另一个方法是 告诉自己出现假正例是正常的
positives, even with a high probability, as long as there's not too many.
即使概率高 只要出现的次数不是太多
In this case,
在这个例子中
you would try to control what is called the false discovery rate, or FDR.
你会试着控制错的发现率或者 FDR
The false discovery rate is the number of false positives, that is, the number
FDR 是假正例出现的次数
of times that you reject the null, even when the null was true, divided by
你拒绝 0 的次数 即使 0 是正确的
the total number of rejections of the null, both valid and invalid.
除以拒绝 0 的总次数 包括有效的和无效的 0
And actually, it's the expected value of this quantity.
实际上 它是这个数量的期望值
What the false discovery rate is measuring is,
FDR 正在测试的是
out of all of the rejections of the null, that is, all of
拒绝 0 的所有次数
the metrics that you declare to have a statistically significant difference.
你宣布的有统计学意义上的差异的所有指标
How many of them had a real difference as opposed to how many were
有多少是真正的差异
false positives?
有多少是假正例？
This really only makes sense if you have a huge number of metrics, say hundreds.
这真的很重要 如果你有大量的指标 例如数百个
So suppose that you have 200 metrics that you're measuring and
假设你有 200 指标在进行测试
you capped the false discovery rate at 0.05.
FDR = 0.05
What this means is that you're okay with having 5 false positives and
这意味着在每个实验中可以出现 5 次假正例
95 true positives in every experiment.
95 次真正例
The family wise error rate, or the overall alpha in this case,
在这个例子中 FWER 或总的 α = 1
would be one, since you have at least one false positive every time.
因为每次至少出现一次假正例
But the false discovery rate is 0.05.
但 FDR = 0.05
Since most of the metrics that you're claiming have a significant difference
因为大多数你声称有巨大差异的指标
actually do.
的事实情况是这样的
So if you're trying to detect significant changes across a large
所以 如果你试着探测许多指标的巨大差异
number of metrics, then capping the false discovery rate
然后得出 FDR
instead of the family wise error rate can be a lot more lenient.
而 FWER 的范围更广
See the instructor's notes for more details about controlling the false
查看讲师注释 了解控制 FDR 的更多详情
discovery rate and some methods you can use to do so.
和一些可以用来这样做的方法